Guide to the A. H. Veazey Field Diaries
A. H. Veazey Field Diaries
1945-1960
1945 1960
Veazey A. H. Alexander Holloway 1895-1963
MC 00192
A. H. (Alexander Holloway) Veazey Field Diaries, 1945-1960, consist of a collection of field diaries written by Veazey for the United States Department of Agriculture Soil Conservation Service. The diaries contain notations about Veazey's route of travel, work done, and observations made, as well as summaries of meetings.
A. H. (Alexander Holloway) Veazey (1895-1963) worked for the United States Department of Agriculture Soil Conservation Service in North Carolina and in other southeastern states. He graduated with a B.S. in Agriculture from the N.C. State College of Agriculture and Engineering (later North Carolina State University) in 1922.
2 linear feet
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Transferred by Edward Morris in 1987 (Accn. no. 1987-0014)
Collection is in chronological order.
A. H. (Alexander Holloway) Veazey (1895-1963) worked for the U.S. Department of Agriculture Soil Conservation Service in North Carolina and in other southeastern states. He graduated with a B.S. in Agriculture from the N.C. State College of Agriculture and Engineering (later North Carolina State University) in 1922.
Field diaries of A. H. Veazey, Assistant Conservationist for the Soil Conservation Service, United States Department of Agriculture. Diaries found in the attic of a residence once owned by Veazey on St. Mary's Street in Raleigh, North Carolina. The collection consists of field diaries written for the U.S. Department of Agriculture Soil Conservation Service.
The diaries are written in small printed books issued by the United States Department of Agriculture Soil Conservation Service. Instructions in the front of each book say:
"The diary should include route of travel, work done, and observations made, digest of conferences held or cross references to designated memos. Also, show time of each change in activity, including the time of each major change in route of travel, and other factors involved in the work of each day.
"Use reverse side of page if necessary to complete the record for a day.
"At the end of each day's diary, enter mileage traveled; mode of travel; expenses incurred; and a general statement of day's activities."
Veazey generally traveled in North Carolina, but occasionally visited South Carolina or Virginia.
Veazey A. H. Alexander Holloway 1895-1963; United States Soil Conservation Service; Veazey A. H. Alexander Holloway 1895-1963; Diaries; Soil conservation Virginia; South Carolina Soil conservation; North Carolina Soil conservation; North Carolina Soil conservationists
- Field diary, 1945 December 10-1946 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Field Diary, 1946 April 1-1946 July7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Field Diary, 1946 July 8-1946 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Field Diary, 1946 October 16-1947 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Field Diary, 1974 February 5-1947 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Field Diary, 1947 May 23-1947 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Field Diary, 1947 September 22-1948 January 14 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Field Diary, 1948 January 14-1948 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Field Diary, 1948 April 23-1948 August 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Field Diary, 1948 August 23-1948 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Field Diary, 1949 March 24-1949 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Field Diary, 1949 July 21-1949 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Field Notebook-No Date (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Field Diary, 1949 November 17-1950 March 6 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Field Diary, 1950 March 7-1950 May 31 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Field Diary, 1950 June 1-1950 September 15 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Fiel Diary, 1950 September 17-1951 January 9 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Field Diary, 1951 January 10-1951 May 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Field Diary, 1951 May 3-1951 August 20 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Field Diary, 1951 August 26-1951 November 30 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Field Diary, 1951 December 3-1952 April 3 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Field Diary, 1952 April 3-1952 July 16 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Field Diary, 1952 July 17-1952 October 20 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Field Diary, 1952 October 21-1953 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Field Diary, 1953 February 7-1953 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Field Diary, 1953 May 15-1953 September 28 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Field Diary, 1953 September 29-1954 January 20 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Field Diary, 1954 January 21-1954 May 5 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Field Diary, 1954 May 6-1954 July 15 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Field Diary, 1954 July 16-1954 September 29 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Field Diary, 1954 September 30-1954 December 8 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Field Diary, 1954 December 9-1955 March 4 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Field Diary, 1955 March 7-1955 June 22 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Field Diary, 1955 June 23-1955 August 31 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Field Diary, 1955 September 1-1955 October 30 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Field Diary, 1955 November 1- 1956 January 26 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Field Diary, 1956 January 27-1956 March 31 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Field Diary, 1956 April 2-1956 June 6 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Field Diary, 1956 June 6-1956 August 7 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Field Diary, 1956 August 8-1956 October 10 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Field Diary, 1956 October 11-1956 December 25 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Field Diary, 1956 December 26-1957 March 11 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Field Diary, 1957 March 12-1957 May 21 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Field Diary, 1957 May 22-1957 July 26 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Field Diary, 1957 July 29-1957 September 29 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Field Diary, 1957 September 30-1957 December 16 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Field Diary, 1957 December 17-1958 February 24 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Field Diary, 1958 February 25-1958 May 5 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Field Diary, 1958 May 6-1958 July 16 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Field Diary, 1958 July 17-1958 September 28 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Field Diary, 1958 September 29-1958 December 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Field Diary, 1958 December 2-1959 February 16 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Field Diary, 1959 February 17-1959 April 26 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Field Diary, 1959 April 27-1959 June 25 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Field Diary, 1959 June 26-1959 September 4 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Field Diary, 1959 September 8-1959-November 16 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Field Diary, 1959 November 17-1960 February 2 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Field Diary, 1960 February 3-1960 April 19 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Field Diary, 1960 April 20-1960 June 29 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Field Diary, 1960 June 30-1960 September 22 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Field Diary, 1960 September 22-1960 September 30 (Box 4, Folder 17)